These are the exact same investment
projections, the numbers haven't changed,
the only difference is how they're shown.
My family calls me the compound growth
preacher.
When I was 18 years old, I came across a
compound interest calculator, and
seeing what a few decades could do to
ordinary contributions absolutely blew
my mind.
And quite frankly, I became a pretty
annoying 18 year old to know.
I was constantly telling people you need
to start investing early.
But eventually, I got more interested in
why those same numbers weren't nearly
as convincing to other people.
And I started wondering whether part of
the problem is how we're representing
compound growth. I had an ambitious
research idea and absolutely no budget.
So of course, the next logical step was
grad school.
During my master's in marketing and
behavioral science, I designed and ran a
six experiment program investigating how
the visual presentation of compound
growth projections can influence
consumers' perceptions of that growth and
their investment motivation.
I own the project from end to end, from
developing the theory, designing and
programming the studies, recruiting
participants, analyzing the data, and
writing up the final paper.
And what I found is that graphs made
compound growth acceleration more
apparent, which increased consumers'
confidence in that growth and led to
higher contributions.
Five experiments later, my family still
groans when the compound growth
soapbox comes out. But unfortunately for
them, I don't plan to stop anytime
soon. I want to keep turning this
obsession into things that I can build,
launch, and improve.
I've spent my entire investing life on the
client side of Wealthsimple, and
now I want to see what I can build from
the other side.
Thank you.